Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Sharp, Elliott, August 2011-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information about his group and solo projects; a list of recent compositions and new releases; a list of lectures and residencies that he has conducted; a list of installations and visual art works; and details about the music that he has composed for film, opera, and theater.
  Elliott Sharp (b. 1951) is an American multi-instrumentalist and composer whose pieces include works for orchestra, opera, chamber, solo, and theater music, as well as pieces for film and installations. As an instrumentalist, Sharp focuses on the guitar and saxophone. His compositions combine styles and genres such as avant-garde, noise, jazz, blues, and techno. He is the leader of the musical projects Carbon and Orchestra Carbon, Tectonics, and Terraplane.
  Terraplane (Blues group)
- Shatin, Judith, August 2011- ongoing; Shatin, Judith, 1949-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of judithshatin.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; her blog; information about her compositions and projects; a calendar of her events; and press and news relating to Shatin.
  Judith Shatin (b. 1949) is a composer of avant-garde instrumental music. Her works make use of non-traditional sound sources as well as electronic instruments and are frequently performed by orchestras. Her repertoire includes chamber, choral, and orchestral music, as well as electronic, electroacoustic, and multimedia pieces. Shatin creative process draws from electronic media and texts from various sources, primarily poets.
- Shaw, Caroline, November 2017- ongoing; Shaw, Caroline (Caroline Adelaide); 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of carolineshaw.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The crawl was rescoped in an attempt to capture Bandcamp files.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; tour dates; contact information; information about her compositions and projects; and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files.
  Embedded WordPress audio on the site was not captured due to technological constraints.
  Caroline Shaw (b. 1982) is a singer, violinist, and composer of classically-influenced vocal and instrumental music. She is the recipient of the Pulitzer Prize in music and a multiple Grammy Award winner. Her work includes pieces created for artists, ensembles, and orchestras of varied musical backgrounds such as Rosalía, Renée Fleming, Yo-Yo Ma, Tiler Peck, Nas, Kanye West, the Los Angeles Philharmonic, and the New York Philharmonic.
- Sheng, Bright, November 2017- ongoing; Sheng, Bright, 1955-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of brightsheng.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; a catalog of his works and recordings; a calendar of recent and upcoming performances; writings about Sheng's work; an interview with the artist; examples of his writings; contact information; a press kit which includes the artist's CV as well as biographies in English and Chinese; and embedded video files pertaining to the premiere performance of one of his works.
  Bright Sheng (b. 1955) is a pianist, conductor, and composer whose works include pieces for opera, theater, ballet, orchestra, chamber, band, chorus, solo, and vocal performances. His orchestral pieces also include music for traditional Chinese instruments. His compositions are influenced by the musical culture of Asia. Notable examples of Sheng's works include Dream of the Red Chamber, H'un: In Memoriam 1966-76, Nanking! Nanking!—a Threnody for Pipa and Orchestra, and Madam Mao.
- Shepherd, Sean, February-July 2015; Shepherd, Sean, 1979-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of seanshepherd.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Sean Shepherd (b. 1979) is a composer of orchestra, ensemble, choir, and solo works based in New York City and Chicago. Notable works by Shepherd include On a clear day, Latticework, Express Abstractionism, Sprout, and Downtime. He is the developer and director of the NYO-USA's Composer Apprentice program with Carnegie Hall's Weill Music Institute.
  The website contained a biography, a list of events, a list of works, and contact information. This description is based on the February 2015 crawl. As of 2023, the website no longer exists. The URL redirects to Shepherd's biography on an external website.
- Shields, Alice, November 2017- ongoing; Shields, Alice, 1943-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of aliceshields.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her compositions and projects; examples of her prose works in the form of audio files; a discography of her published albums; press features and news relating to Shields; a list of articles written by the composer for the publication NewMusicBox; and contact information.
  Alice Shields (b. 1943) is a composer of operas, as well as vocal and electronic music with a feminist theme. Shields' work draws from multiple musical traditions such as the Noh Theater of Japan and the Bharatanatyam dance-drama of India. Examples of Shields' operas include the titles Jack Dunne's Revenge, Shaman, Shivatanz, and Criseyde.
- Shin, Myungsoo, February 2014- ongoing; Myungsoo, Shin; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://myungsoo.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Vimeo video files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist written in Korean; information about his compositions and projects; news relating to Shin and his works; a catalog of his music; and reels of his work in the form of embedded video files.
  Myungsoo Shin is a composer of instrumental music for the stage, television, and live performance. His pieces make use of classical, jazz, contemporary, electronic, and world music techniques and styles.
- Siegel, Aaron, February 2014- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of aaronsiegel.net and experimentsinopera.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The composer's website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; a calendar of his events; press relating to Siegel and his works; and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The crawl also includes the website for Experiments in Opera, a composer-driven non-profit opera company.
  Embedded YouTube and Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Aaron Siegel (b. 1977) is a composer of music for percussion instruments, ensembles, and operas. He also has a background as an improvising percussionist and band leader. Since 2011, he is a leading member of Experiments in Opera.
- Sierra, Arlene, November 2017- ongoing; Sierra, Arlene Elizabeth, 1970-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of arlenesierra.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about her compositions and projects; a calendar of her events; a catalog of her works; press and news relating to the artist and her compositions; a gallery of images of the artist; a discography of her published albums; news; interviews; and reviews relating to Sierra; and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio and video files.
  Embedded Flash player audio files on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Arlene Sierra (b. 1970) is a contemporary American composer based in London. Sierra's music is classically-influenced and instrumental. Her works are primarily for orchestral and small or large ensemble performance. Examples of Sierra's notable premieres include Nature Symphony, Butterflies Remember a Mountain, and Game of Attrition.
- Sierra, Roberto, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of robertosierra.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Roberto Sierra (b. 1953) is a Puerto Rican composer of orchestra and ensemble music. Some of his notable works include Missa Latina, Sinfonía No. 4, and Concierto Barroco. He is a Grammy-nominated composer and a Latin Grammy winner. In 2021, he was elected to the American Academy of Arts and Letters.
  The website contains a biography, an events calendar, a list of works, videos, audio, reviews, recordings, and contact information. This description is based on the March 2023 crawl.
- Silva, Pedro Henriques da, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The composer's website contains information on his film compositions; videos and audio; a catalogue of orchestral, chamber, vocal, and solo works; information on his project Echoes of Nature; a list of Henriques da Silva's partnering institutions; press excerpts; information about his duo Tango Fado featuring bandoneónist Daniel Binelli; an introduction to Manhattan Camerata, the project he co-founded with his wife Lucía Caruso; videos about his project Tritoneking; and information about Transclassical Music, a genre that was coined by Caruso. This description was updated in March 2025.
  Manhattan Camerata is a chamber music ensemble that composes western classical chamber orchestra with world instruments (Portuguese guitar, bandoneón, sitar, darbuka, and others). The group members are Lucía Caruso and Pedro H. da Silva. The website contains information on their weekly live streams, transclassical music definition, albums, film scores, videos, events and the Tango Fado Project.
  Pedro Henriques da Silva is a Portuguese composer and classical guitar professor. His composition style includes contemporary classical, world, film, rock, jazz and electronica. He performs and works with his partner, Argentine composer and pianist Lucía Caruso. Together, they founded the chamber orchestra Manhattan Camerata and are co-owners of Light & Sound Scoring, a New York-based film music company. Henriques da Silva is a member of the New York University faculty.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of pedrodasilva.com and manhattancamerata.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Singleton, Alvin, February 2015-ongoing; Singleton, Alvin, 1940-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of alvinsingleton.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Alvin Singleton (b. 1940) is an American composer for theatre, orchestra, solo instruments, and chamber ensembles. Notable works by Singleton include his orchestral work When Given a Choice; TRUTH, a work for chorus, ensemble, and dance based on the life of Sojourner Truth; and Through it All, a piece for wind quintet.
  The website features a biography, news, a list of works, recordings, press coverage, photos, and contact information.
- Sinha, Samita, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of samitasinha.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Samita Sinha (b. 1978) is a composer of multidisciplinary performance works whose music is inspired by Indian vocal traditions. Through her art, Sinha uses the body "to create a decolonized, multivalent language of voice and vibration." Her works include The Medead, Tongues in Trees, Cipher, bewilderment, This ember state, Infinity Folds, Tear, and Tremor.
  The website features a biography; a list of works with descriptions and images; an events calendar; press information; and contact information.
- Sims, Ezra, April 2014-February 2015, March 2025-ongoing; Sims, Ezra, 1928-2015; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ezrasims.com and ezrasims.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Ezra Sims (1928-2015) was a composer and a pioneer of microtonal music. He was a co-founder and president of the Dinosaur Annex Music Ensemble, as well as the co-designer of Micro, a font designed for microtonal music composition.
  The website contains a biography, a bibliography, a list of works, press information, photos, and contact information.
- Smith, Kile, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of kilesmith.com, wp.com/kilesmith.com, and kilesmith.wordpress.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Kile Smith (b. 1956) is a Grammy-nominated composer of choral, orchestra, ensemble, and solo instrumental music. Notable titles by Smith include Thirty Variations on a Theme of Bartók (2022) and The Arc in the Sky (2020). He is also a nature photographer.
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, an events calendar, press reviews, blog posts, essays, and his photography. The description is based on the March 2023 crawl.
- Smith, Wadada Leo, November 2017- ongoing; Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quartet; Smith, Wadada Leo, 1941-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of wadadaleosmith.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a discography of Smith's published albums; information about his artistic philosophy and the creation of the language Ankhrasmation; details about his ensembles; news about the artist and his performances; a biography of Smith; information about the Kiom Kabell Foundation and the CREATE Festival; information about his musical repertoire and projects; images of the artist and his visual art pieces; a store of his music, visual art, and scores; embedded video files of Smith's music; and a section dedicated to his album Fire Illuminations.
  Wadada Leo Smith (b. 1941) is a trumpet player, multi-instrumentalist, and composer of jazz and blues influenced music. He has participated and led a variety of musical ensembles, including the RedKoral Quartet, Najwa, and Golden Quintet. Smith is the creator of a symbolic image-based language for performers and musicians called Ankhrasmation. The Kiom Kabell Foundation and the CREATE Festival are two initiatives that preserve and disseminate the work and musical philosophy of Smith. Major projects by him include Ten Freedom Summers, Rosa Parks Oratorio, and America's National Parks.
  Wadada Leo Smith's Silver Orchestra; Wadada Leo Smith's Organic (Musical group); Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quintet; Wadada Leo Smith's Golden Quartet
- Smooke, David, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5895; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.davidsmooke.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a list of his works; news related to his work; audio files and videos; photos; and an online store.
  David Smooke (b. 1969) is a theater director, producer, and stagehand residing in Baltimore, Maryland. He performs improvisations and original pieces on several instruments, including a toy piano. His compositions include works for large ensemble, chamber ensemble, non-standard chamber groupings, voice, duo, and solo performers. He is also professor of music theory, rock music history, and composition, as well as the Chair of the Music Theory Department at the Peabody Conservatory of Johns Hopkins University. In the past, he served as co-composer and curator for the Lunar Ensemble and the League of the Unsound Sound.
- Snider, Sarah Kirkland, February 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of sarahkirklandsnider.com and sarahkirklandsnider.github.io/Gloria in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The crawl was rescoped in an attempt to capture video and audio files.
  The artist's website contains a biography of Snider; information about her compositions and projects; news and press relating to the artist; a calendar of her events; and examples of her work in the form of embedded audio and video files. The crawl also includes an interactive GitHub website of a movement titled Gloria from Sarah Kirkland Snider's Mass for the Endangered, on the subject of endangered animals and the climate crisis.
  Embedded image files, audio, and SoundCloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Sarah Kirkland Snider (b. 1973) is an American composer of chamber, orchestral, song cycle, choral, and ballet works. Notable examples of compositions by the artist include Penelope (2010), Unremembered (2015), Mass for the Endangered (2020), and The Blue Hour (2022).
- Snowden, Steven, February 2014- ongoing; Snowden, Steven, 1981-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of stevensnowden.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; a discography of his published albums; examples of Snowden's work in the form of embedded audio and video files; and a calendar of his events.
  Embedded YouTube and Vimeo video files and SoundCloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Steven Snowden (b. 1981) is a Boston-based composer of bluegrass, folk, and rock-influenced instrumental music for dance, theater, installations, and concert performance. His compositions include pieces for brass, large ensemble, percussion, string, and woodwind instruments.
- Snyder, Jeff, February 2014-ongoing; Snyder, Jeff, 1978-; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of scattershot.org and scatter.server295.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a catalog of his instrumental inventions; information about his compositions and projects; a list of his talks and publications; a discography of his published albums; press information; and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The crawl also includes Sunspots, a virtual installation by Jeff Snyder and Drew Wallace.
  Jeff Snyder (b. 1978) is a composer of improvisational and notated music who makes use of the electronic instruments he designs and builds, as well as traditional instruments. Snyder is a founder and lead designer of Snyderphonics, the company through which he builds performance instruments for musicians. One such example is Manta, a sound creation device that has a touch-sensitive interface for music and video control. Snyder is also a member of various musical groups and the co-founder of Carrier Records, an experimental music label.
- Sokolović, Ana, February 2015-ongoing; Sokolović, Ana, 1968-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, a news page, an events calendar, multimedia, and contact information. The website is available in French and English.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of anasokolovic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Ana Sokolović (b. 1968) is a composer born in Belgrade, Yugoslavia (present Serbia) who has been based in Montreal, Canada since 1992. Sokolović is the Artistic Director of the Quebec Contemporary Music Society and a professor of composition at l'Université de Montréal. Her works are inspired by Balkan folklore, and include vocal and instrumental pieces. She has created operas as well as solo, duo, chamber, orchestral, and film compositions.
- Sonami, Laetitia, February 2015-ongoing; Sonami, Laetitia de Compiègne; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of sonami.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Laetitia Sonami (b. 1957) is a French sound artist, performer, and researcher based in the United States. Her compositional focus is electronic music, which she has been pursuing since the 1970s, when the genre was still emerging. Sonami's repertoire includes sound performances, live film collaborations, and sound installations. She is also the creator of instruments that she uses in her performances. One such example is the elbow-length lady's glove, which has motion-tracking sensors. The instrument is considered a precursor of the wearables and gestural controllers used by sound artists in the present.
  The website features news about the artist, a list of works, archived writings, events, media, a biography, teaching information, press coverage, blog posts, and contact information.
- Sonenberg, Daniel, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website www.danielsonenberg.com contains a biography of the artist; information about his opera compositions The Summer King and Girl in Six Beats: A Chamber Opera in One Act; audio and video recordings of his other music; a section of upcoming events announcements; his blog; links to press reviews of his work; and his contact information. The website located at www.danielsonenberg.org does not exist at this URL as of 2023.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of danielsonenberg.com and danielsonenberg.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Daniel Sonenberg (b.1970) is a composer of orchestra, vocal, chamber, ensemble, and rock music; performer; and educator based in Portland, Maine. Sonenberg is the composer of The Summer King, a two-act opera on the life of Josh Gibson, an American baseball catcher. Sonenberg worked on The Summer King for over ten years in collaboration with the Brooklyn-based company The American Opera Project. Other compositions by Sonenberg include kintsukoroi (2021) for violin and piano; and But Why? (2020), a piece for two performers using drums, saxophone, electric bass guitar, piano, voice, and live looping. Sonenberg's rock music includes both solo releases, as well as albums created with his band Lovers of Fiction. He is also a music academic specializing in the work of singer-songwriter Joni Mitchell, having completed his doctoral dissertation at the City University of New York about her.
- Soper, Kate, February 2015-ongoing; Soper, Kate, 1981-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of katesoper.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.